Speaker: This painting is a self-portrait by the
Dutch painter Vincent Van Gogh.
Van Gogh was born in Delft, in the Netherlands,
on the thirtieth of March eighteen fifty-three.
His parents weren’t poor – his father was
a church minister, and his mother was an artist.
There is only one known photograph of him,
which is when he was nineteen years old.
We only have an idea of what he looked like as
an adult because of his many self-portraits.
He painted thirty-five, all in the last four years of his life.
He painted so many self-portraits because he was very poor,
and it was cheaper than paying models.
In eighteen eighty-eight, when he was thirty-five,
Van Gogh was in Arles, in the south of France.
He was happy there because the light
and the colours were beautiful. His friend, painter Paul Gaugin,
was with him in Arles for a short time.
Van Gogh was not strong mentally, and the relationship between
Van Gogh and Gaugin was difficult.
After a big fight, Van Gogh cut off part of his ear.
He later painted a self-portrait with the injured ear.
After that he was in a psychiatric hospital for some time
in the south of France.
This was his last self-portrait. He painted it in September
eighty eighty-nine when he was in the hospital.
In this self-portrait, we see Van Gogh as a painter for the very first time.
Van Gogh died a few months later,
on the twenty-ninth of July eighteen ninety.
He was only thirty-seven years old.
His paintings weren’t popular during his lifetime
and he was never rich or famous.
But today Van Gogh’s pictures are everywhere.
People think that he is one of the greatest painters in the world,
and his paintings, like Sunflowers, and The Starry Night,
sell for millions of pounds.